RG 004:067, Hebron Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Hebron Probate Court records
1784-1975, 1998
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Hebron District)
24.25 cubic feet
Record books, 1784-1976; Probate files, 1833, 1851-1975, 1998.
RG004_067
1950-001, 2011-123, 2012-029, and 2013-019
Historical Note
Hebron, Tolland County, Town established on May 26, 1708
The Hebron Probate District was constituted May 1789, from the East Haddam Probate District. It also served the following municipalities at various times: Andover, May 1848 - June 1851; Bolton, May 1789 - June 1851; Columbia May 1808 - June 1851; Vernon, October 1808 - May 1814. The Hebron Probate District merged with the Glastonbury Probate District on January 5, 2011 to create the Glastonbury - Hebron Probate District which serves the municipalities of Glastonbury and Hebron.
Town of Hebron, Probate District chronology:
May 1708 - October 1741, Hartford District
October 1741 - May 1789, East Haddam District
May 1789 - January 4, 2011, Hebron District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Glastonbury - Hebron District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, Volumes 1-20, 1784-1849, and Ledgers A & B, 1826-1862; Volumes 1-16, 1851-1976, and Ledger, 1851-1875. Contact the probate court to access original record books after Volume 16. When the Andover probate district was created from the Hebron probate district in 1851, the Hebron district record books were kept in Andover where the court had been held. From that point the Hebron probate district began numbering their records books with number 1. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1833, 1851-1975, 1998. Most of the records of Hebron Probate District previous to June 27, 1851 are with the Andover Probate District records. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1833, 1851-1897 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books in accession 2011-123 are numbered consecutively from 1 to 16. There is also a Ledger volume labeled "A".
Record books in accession 2013-019 are numbered consecutively from 1 to 20. There is also two Ledger volumes labeled "A" and "B".
Probate files in accession 1950-001 are arranged alphabetically.
Probate files in accession 2012-029 are arranged as received from the Probate Court.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. Note: CSL does not hold any original record books. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1950-001 are represented in this index.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the probate files in accession 2012-029.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Andover; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Bolton; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Columbia; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Coventry; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Hebron; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Vernon
Places:
Andover (Conn.); Bolton (Conn.); Columbia (Conn.); Coventry (Conn.); Hebron (Conn.); Vernon (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Probate files from 1921-1976 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Removals of parent as guardian of minor (all documents) and terminations of parental rights (all documents) from October 1, 1975 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
Accession 2011-123, Record books, 1851-1976, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-21, 1789-1851; and volumes 1-10, 1851-1937; probate files, 1851-1915; and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1950-001 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): January 24, 1950 (1833-1897).
The record books in accession 2011-123 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on April 19, 2011.
The probate files in accession 2012-029 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on April 12, 2012.
The record books in accession 2013-019 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on December 5, 2012.
Container List
- Record books, 1784-1862; 9 cubic feet (22 volumes); 2013-019
  - Records, 1784-1796 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1796-1803 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1803-1806 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1806-1810 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1810-1814 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1814-1816 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1816-1819 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1819-1822 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1823-1826 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1826-1829 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1829-1833 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1833-1836 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1836-1840 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1840-1842 (Volume 14)
  - Records, 1842-1844 (Volume 15)
  - Records, 1844-1845 (Volume 16)
  - Records, 1845-1846 (Volume 17)
  - Records, 1846-1848 (Volume 18)
  - Records, 1848 (Volume 19)
  - Records, 1848-1849 (Volume 20)
  - Ledger, 1826-1848 (Volume A)
  - Ledger, 1849-1862 (Volume B)
- Record books, 1851-1976; 12 cubic feet (19 volumes); 2011-123
  - Records, 1851-1856 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1856-1861 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1861-1864 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1864-1871 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1871-1876 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1876-1885 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1885-1895 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1895-1903 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1903-1912 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1912-1936 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1916-1945 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1928-1946 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1937-1968 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1943-1959 (Volume 14)
  - Records, 1956-1975 (Volume 15)
  - Records, 1975-1976 (Volume 16)
  - General index, 2 volumes (Volume unnumbered)
  - Ledger, 1851-1875 (Volume A)
- Probate files, 1833, 1851-1897; 3.25 cubic feet; 1950-001
  - Adams - Bliss (Drawer 1)
  - Bradford - Cooley (Drawer 2)
  - Cowles - Glover (Drawer 3)
  - Gott - Jones, R. (Drawer 4)
  - Jones, S. - Mann (Drawer 5)
  - Martindale - Phelps (Drawer 6)
  - Porter - Raymond (Drawer 7)
  - Richards - Strong (Drawer 8)
  - Sumner - Way (Drawer 9)
  - Webster - Z; Miscellaneous (Drawer 10)
- Inventory Control Book, 1833, 1851-1897; T003073
  Index of the probate files in accession 1950-001
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Probate Files, 1848-1998, bulk 1898-1975; 9 cubic feet; 2012-029
  - Probate files, 1848-1998, bulk 1898-1975 (Box 1-9)